Edgar Ivanov

Flat 3, Fonda Court, 3 Premiere Place – London, E14 8SD **☎** +44 7531-142-133 • ⊠ ivanovedgar@gmail.com www.ivanovedgar.me

Profile

Tenacious Computer Science graduate with genuine passion for hardware and proven troubleshooting skills gained during the Industrial Placement with Information Services department of Aberystwyth University and the following year spent working in first line customer support.

Key Achievements and Skills

- Certified Apple Macintosh Technician
- Networked equipment setup and management
 PowerShell and Bash scripting
- MFD installation and maintenance
- Repairing IT equipment and replacing parts
- Windows/Unix Server configuration
- Knowledge of the Active Directory
- Windows OS Deployment with WDS/WAIK
- SNMP Network Management System
- Roll-out of 3CX VoIP phone system

Programming Languages.

Java

Assembler

SQL (MySQL/PostgreSQL)

o C/C++

HTML5/XHTML/CSS

Education

Aberystwyth University

BSc (Hons) Mobile And Wearable Computing, 2:2, Inc Integrated Industrial And Professional Training

- System and Network Administration (74)
- Computer Architecture And Hardware (76)
- Modelling Persistent Data (59)

- C And Unix Programming (60)
 - Computer Hardware & Operating Systems (64)
 - Mathematics (70)

A. Pushkin Gymnasium

Secondary Education

- A level equivalent
 - English A (62)
 - History B (49)
 - Lithuanian A (50)

Kaunas, Lithuania

September 1998 - June 2010

Aberystwyth, UK

September 2010 - June 2014

- 11 GCSE equivalent grades A* C
 - IT (A)
 - Physics (A)
 - History (A)

Work Experience

Aberystwyth University, Information Services

Customer Services Assistant

Aberystwyth, UK

August 2013 - June 2014

- Provided 1^{st} line IT support, by phone and face to face.
- Troubleshooted problems with customer laptops and phones at the desk.
- Provided guidance on the use of the IS services.
- Focused at being my best every day for the customers, learned to listen actively and communicate effectively.

Aberystwyth University, Information Services

Aberystwyth, UK

Industrial Year Placement

July 2012 - August 2013

- Provided 1^{st} and 2^{nd} line IT support.
- Carried out computer and ICT equipment maintenance in workshop and on client site.
- Installed and upgraded hardware and peripherals.
- Identified, investigated and documented solutions to all the types of computing problems.
- Developed strong time management and problem solving skills.
- Built the deep knowledge of Apple Mac Computers and Windows Server configuration.

McDonald's Restaurant Aberystwyth, UK June 2011 - July 2012

Crew Member

- Greeted customers, took and assembled orders and received payments.
- Followed restaurant's sanitation procedures and policies.
- Checked equipment to ensure it was working efficiently.
- Gained communication, teamwork and customer services skills.
- Learnt how to be a good McDonald's slave.

Personal Projects

ivanovedgar.wordpress.com/

My Industrial Year Placement blog

July 2012 - August 2013

github.com/ivanovedgar

Contains personal projects and university assignments

Present

Interests

I have a keen interest in new technologies and enjoy reading IT journals in my spare time, mainly focusing on hardware development. Working with open source projects related to the CMS, home media servers and Raspberry Pi. I also own a VPS that hosts my personal website and is being used for VPN. Enjoy hiking with friends and regularly explore National Trust places in the holidays.

Languages

English: Fluent Russian: Native Lithuanian: Native

References

Jan Litton: Team leader

Information Services Department

Hugh Owen Building, D.7 Aberystwyth University

Penglais, Aberystwyth, Ceredigion

SY23 3DZ

E-Mail: jpl@aber.ac.uk

Fred Labrose: Final year project supervisor

Computer Science Department

Physical Science Building Aberystwyth University

Penglais, Aberystwyth, Ceredigion

SY23 3DA

E-Mail: ffl@aber.ac.uk